

2510 Kittredge Loop Dr, 149 ANDR, Boulder, CO, 80310

□ (970) 290-9205 | ■ dylan.mcnally@colorado.edu | 🖀 www.dylanmcnally.com | 🛅 Dylan McNally

"All we have to decide is what to do with the time that is given us." ~Gandalf

Summary .

Undergraduate student at the University of Colorado at Boulder. Pursuing my dream of becoming a professor of physics at a university, with an emphasis in experimental atomic and quantum research. I am a self proclaimed physics nerd. As a lover of 'doing' I enjoy working with my hands to physically realize the contents of my head. I find my greatest accomplishments in having supported others in their achievements. My hobbies include DIY projects, exploring the outdoors, Russian literature, and, of course, coffee.

Education

University of Colorado at Boulder

Boulder, CO

B.S. IN ENGINEERING PHYSICS, B.S. IN APPLIED MATHEMATICS

August 2015 - May 2019

- GPA: 3.899
- · Minor in Leadership Studies

SUMMA CUM LAUDE, SALUTATORIAN

Loveland High School

Loveland, CO

August 2011 - May 2015

- GPA: 4.43
- · National AP Scholar

Work Experience

Joint Institute for Laboratory Astrophysics

Boulder, CO

Undergraduate Research Assistant

May 2017 - Present

- Conduct research, writing undergraduate honors thesis with Professor Cindy Regal.
- · Fabricated first successful phononic crystal membrane resonator for the Regal Group. Measured advanced resonators for integration in optical cavities and magnetic force sensing assemblies.
- Integrated advanced membrane designs into magnetic force sensing systems.

Univ. of Colorado at Boulder

Boulder, CO

RESIDENT ADVISOR - ANDREWS HALL

August 2016 - Present

- · Foster community building within the residence hall. Live-in position that seeks to make the halls a safe, thriving community for residents. I have encountered mental health cases, severe intoxication, medical emergencies, peer-peer conflict, and more.
- Mentor residents in the hall and provide them with resources to enable them to reach their full potential.

Presidents Leadership Class

Boulder, CO

CLASS ADVISOR, DIRECTOR OF CLASS ADVISORS

August 2017 - Present

- · Assist in teaching the first year course for the Presidents Leadership Class. Lead small group breakouts, facilitate discussion and debate, and critique student writing all concerning ethical leadership and community issues.
- · Lead and direct academic student staff. Serve as a resource for class advisors to excel in their roles. Communication channel from professional staff.

Microfabrication Laboratory - Univ. of Colorado

Boulder, CO

ASSISTANT LABORATORY MANAGER

May 2016 - August 2017

- · Assisted the laboratory manager in administrative tasks, chemical monitoring, safety protocol, and general lab maintenance.
- Orchestrated two laboratory moves.
- Initiated and created laboratory inventories for chemicals, equipment, and materials.

Dept. of Mechanical Engineering - Univ. of Colorado

Boulder, CO

Undergraduate Research Assistant, Y.C. Lee Group

October 2015 - September 2017

- · Studied properties of wicking structures of both flexible and high heat flux vapor chambers in pursuit of creating an optimization model for future designs with Professor Y.C. Lee.
- Developed testing methods for characterization of wicking structure permeability and capillary pressure (paper in preparation).
- Design and fabrication of novel structures to increase vapor chamber performance.
- Partnered with Kelvin Thermal Technologies and Murata Manufacturing.

Boulder, CO

LEARNING ASSISTANT January 2017 - May 2017

 Wrote homework solutions, graded homeworks and exams, and hosted weekly office hours and review sessions for the students in APPM 3310: Matrix Methods and Applications

Honors & Awards

2018	Goldwater Scholarship Nominee, Univ. of Colorado	Boulder, CO
2016-2017 Discovery Learning Apprentice , College of Engineering and Applied Science		Boulder, CO
2016	Directors Club Scholar, Univ. of Colorado	Boulder, CO
2015	Semifinalist. Boettcher Foundation Scholarship	Loveland. CO

Skills

Programming Python, Fortran, Matlab, C++

Micro-/nanofabrication Lithography, evaporative deposition, wet etching, general cleanroom pratices

Computer Aided Design Certified Solidworks Associate, COMSOL Multiphysics, AutoCAD

General Software Microsoft Office, github, Mathematica **Manufacturing** Basic machining and woodworking skills

Involvement

Engineering Honors Program

Boulder, CO

Student Leader August 2015 - Present

· Mentored students in a culture and community based honors program. Helped maintain the coffee and tea bar and organized

• Project lead for Continuous Arm Chronograph, student designed and fabricated mechanical clock.

Presidents Leadership Class STUDENT STAFF MEMBER, SCHOLAR

Boulder, CO

August 2015 - Present

• Engaged in and facilitated discussions surrounding leadership development and practice.

- Engaged in and racilitated discussions surrounding leadership develo
- Served on student staff as a first year class advisor.
- Initiated PLC branding, orchestrated apparel order and distribution.
- PLC Day of Service volunteer 2015, 2016.
- 2016-2017 Sophomore Cohort Ambassador.

Undergraduate Research

Boulder, CO

Advocate, Researcher October 2015 - Present

- Engaged in research as a student, 2015 to present.
- Assisted in hiring undergraduate students for research positions.
- Presented in physics department research interest session, 2017.
- Presented in Presidents Leadership Class research interest session, 2017.
- Attended undergraduate research symposiums to support fellow researchers.

Andrews Hall Book Club Boulder, CO

Member August 2015 - August 2017

• Read and discussed various short stories, Being and Nothingness by Friedrich Nietzsche, and The Brothers Karamazov by Fyodor Dostoyevsky

CU Club Swim and Dive

Boulder, CO

Мемвеr August 2015 - May 2016

· 2016 National Qualifier